(
"ai_sub_version": "2.9.1",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 7,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch"
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 5,
"max": 5,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
刮目せよ！
Feast your eyes!
もう！
Jeez!
刮目せよ！
Feast your eyes!
プロデューサー！！！
Producer!!!
どうしたんですか、ラプラスさん。
What is the matter, La+?
次の生誕ライブ、なんにもやることないんですけど！！
I have absolutely nothing to do for my next birthday live concert!!
毎年いろいろやってきたけど...
I've done various things every year, but...
去年はミームやりすぎて、ミームキャラになっちゃったし、どうしよう！
last year I did too many memes and became a meme character, so what should I do?!
デビュー当時のアイドルらしさは もう見る影もないですからね。
After all, there's no trace left of the idol-like quality you had when you debuted.
吾輩は、どうやっていけば良いんだー！
What on earth should I do?!
勝手にTier表とか作っちゃいましたし…
We went ahead and made a tier list without asking...
それだ！！！
That's it!
ほら、吾輩、お姉さん大好きでしょ？
Look, I absolutely love big sisters, right?
ホロライブのお姉さん大集合させよう！
Let's gather all the big sisters of Hololive!
お姉さんライブだ！！！
It's an Onee-san Live!
大丈夫だよ！当てはある！吾輩に任せとけ！
It'll be fine! I have someone in mind! Leave it to me!
それはちゃんとラプラスさんのライブとして成立するんですか？
Will that actually work as your own live concert, Laplus-san?
そこは…なんか良い感じにやるんだよ！
Well... we'll somehow make it work!
ていうか、吾輩のこと好きなファンならさ、やっぱり、吾輩が好きなことしてるところ、楽しく見てくれるんじゃない？
I mean, if they're fans who like me, they'll surely enjoy seeing me do what I love, right?
限度があるんじゃないですか？
Isn't there a limit to that?
とにかく、やるって決めたらやるの！いくぞー！！！
Anyway, once I decide to do it, I do it! Let's go!!!
ノエルさん！
Noel-san!
どうしたの？ラプちゃん？
What's the matter, Lap-chan?
実は、もうすぐ吾輩の生誕ライブがあるんですけど、よかったらノエルさんにも出てほしいなって…
Actually, my birthday live concert is coming up soon, and I was wondering if you'd like to perform in it, Noel-san...
えー！ラプちゃん誘ってくれるの！？嬉しい！もちろん、だよ！
Eh! You're inviting me, Lap-chan?! I'm so happy! Of course I will!
よーし、団長、歌とダンス頑張っちゃおうかな！先輩として、かっこいいところ見せちゃうよー！！！
All right, as the Knight Commander, I'll do my best with singing and dancing! As your senior, I'll show you my cool side!!!
あ、いや…歌は吾輩がやるんで…ね？ほら、これ持って！
Ah, well... I'll be doing the singing... okay? Here, hold this!
え、なにになに？どういうこと？これって、うちわ？
Eh, wait, what? What do you mean? Is this... a fan?
さて、あとは何を歌うかですね…
Now, all that's left is deciding what to sing...
一曲目はね、きっとノエルさんも喜んでくれるはず！
For the first song, I'm sure you'll love it, Noel-san!
え！？団長が！？
Eh!? Me?!
去年からノエルさんの影響からか、吾輩のファン層が広がって、こういう曲が喜んでもらえるかなー！って思って！
Maybe because of your influence since last year, my fanbase has expanded, so I thought they'd enjoy this kind of song!
えー！期待しちゃうけど…いいのお！？
Wow! You're getting my hopes up... Is it really okay?!
良いですよー！一曲目盛り上がっていきましょー！
Yes, of course! Let's get hyped up for the first song!
きたー！
It's here!
存外見掛け倒しな虚勢張ってるロマンス
Contrary to popular belief, this romance is all a bluff
組み換えちゃって遺伝子オンリーロンリーエマージェンシー
Recombine those genes, it's a lonely love emergency!
トゥケトゥケな電波に乗った感情論
Emotional attachment carried on fuzzy radio waves
僕のアッピル見逃さないでよ やだやだ やだやだ
Don't miss my appeal, no way, no way, no way!
人間なんてだれだってこういうのが好きなんですって
They say every human being likes this kind of thing
乱れ打ち
Wild flailing!
あーっ！ ラブくんの時代が来た！
Ah! Love-kun's era has come!
ショタかわちいよ！
You're a cute shota!
ラブくん！ 輝いてる！
Love-kun! You're shining!
最後まで輝いてー！
Keep shining until the end!
はぁ、はぁ...
Haah, haah...
さすがに先輩をファン扱いするのはどうかと思いますよ？
I don't think it's right to treat your senior like a fan, you know?
いや、ノエルさんはファンでしょ！ファンっていうか、ママになろうとしてる人...？
No, Noel-san IS a fan! Or rather, someone who's trying to be my mommy...?
とにかく、めっちゃ盛り上がってましたやん！
Anyway, she was super hyped!
てか、てか、お姉さんといえば、ホロライブって学校みたいじゃない？
Speaking of big sisters, isn't Hololive kind of like a school?
学校？
A school?
学校のみんなのアイドル...そらさん。
The school's idol... Sora-san.
隣のクラスの留学生...キアラさん。
The exchange student in the next class... Kiara-san.
凛とした清楚な先輩...AZKiさん。
The dignified, pure senior... AZKi-san.
部活の先輩お姉さま...ネリッサ。
My club senior and big sister... Nerissa.
クールビューティーな先生...クロニー。
The cool beauty teacher... Kronii.
そして、同じクラスにいる、うるさい幼馴染の同級生...いろは。
And my noisy classmate who's also my childhood friend... Iroha.
そうだ！これをライブでやれば盛り上がること間違いなし！そうと決まれば早速突撃だー！
That's it! If we do this in a live concert, there's no doubt it'll be a hit! Now that that's settled, time to raid her room!
次から次へとすごい行動力だ...
Such amazing initiative, one thing after another...
いろはーー！
Iroha!
うん？なんでござるか？
Hmm? What is it degozaru?
ライブでやりたい曲あるんだけど、見ててくんない？
There's a song I want to perform live, can you watch it for me?
見、見る？どういうことでござる？
Wa... watch? What do you mean by that?
そう！見るだけ！やっぱり幼馴染と言えば、いつでも見守ってくれる存在だからね...
Yes! Just watch! After all, childhood friends are always there to watch over you...
ただそこにいるだけで良い、そばにいてくれるだけ、その温かさが染みるんだ...
Just being there is enough, just staying by my side, that warmth is so comforting...
え...なんか気持ち悪いでござる...
Uh... that's kind of creepy, degozaru...
いいからいいから！さ、行くぞー！
Never mind that! Come on, let's go!
え？
Eh?
なにこれ
What is this?
な、なになにこれ
W-What, what, what is this?
なにこれ、な、な、な、なにこれ？
What is this, w-w-w-what is this?
え？何？
Eh? What?
何？
What?
え？
Eh?
ラプラスさん？
Laplus-san?
おお、おお...
Oh, oh...
おお？ええ？
Oh? Eh?
とりあえずさっきから気になっているあの娘
Anyway, that girl I've been eyeing for a while...
あの娘って誰でござるか？
Who's "that girl" degozaru?
ばっちり目が合うのに　気もそぞろな態度
Our eyes meet perfectly, yet she acts so listless
いや、目が合ってるのは...
No, the one whose eyes are meeting...
いやいや、いや、いや、別に好きとかそんなんじゃないよ？
No, no, no, no, it's not like I like her or anything!
ただちょっと、ちょっと、ちょっと、ちょっと、目で追っかけてるだけだってばー！
I'm just, just, just, just following her with my eyes, I swear!
ぶっちゃけ君に結構メロメロなんだってば
To be honest, I'm pretty crazy about you
え、誰に？
Eh, who?
勉強も全然頭に入ってこなくって、やばいやばい！
None of my studies are going into my head, this is bad, so bad!
君にイエス・フォーリンラブ
I've fallen in love with you!
怖いでござるって！
That's scary degozaru!
ほら罰ゲームの真似事？好奇の目で見られてるご近所さんが直接物申すと行ってきます！
Look, acts of punishment game? I'm going to go make a direct complaint to the neighbors who are staring at me!
怖いですって！
It's scary!
やべえ！
This is bad!
こういうのをライブでやるんでござるか！？
Are you going to do this kind of thing in a live concert!?
やめろって言ってんだろ！
I told you to stop!
ピッピッピッとBOSS待ちD-C-D-C神聖神聖　乗ってくってく脳内満ちてく
Pi-pi-pi, waiting for the BOSS, D-C-D-C, divine divine, riding it, filling up my brain,
足りない足りない足りない足りない足りないドキドキしちゃう　君の君の君の君の...
not enough, not enough, not enough, not enough, my heart's pounding, your, your, your, your...
おっきい！
BIG ONE!
見せて見せてもっと見せて見せてちょっと見せて見せて見せて見せて A-B-C-D-E-F-Gッツ
Show me, show me, show me more, show me a little, show me, show me, A-B-C-D-E-F-G-tsu
我慢ショート　我慢マイル　我慢できない
Patience short, patience mile, I can't hold back anymore!
したいしたいし思春期　いたいのいたいのとんでいけ
I want to do it, I want to, it's puberty, pain pain go away!
お、怒っちゃだめでござる...え？
Y-You shouldn't get mad degozaru... Eh?
三年目の浮気心外ね！拍手喝采 先輩！　そんなに近付けられたら　ほだされちゃうわ真ん中って
Three years of cheating? How unexpected! Applause for you, Senpai! If you get that close, you'll melt my heart right in the middle!
そして整理のつかない気持ちに スカッと1000%ちょっとだけ最高
And into these unsettled feelings, a refreshing 1000%, just a little bit of the best!
じーっと見てるでござるよ！
I'm watching you closely!
自分でやるんでござるか？
Are you going to do this yourself?
ママにお肉の生姜焼き
Pork ginger-fry for Mom!
先輩に告白大作戦！
Great confession plan to Senpai!
上に行って　下に行って
Up we go, down we go!
ファイヤー撃ち撃ち大合戦！
Fire shoot-shoot great battle!
どっちを選ぶの？
Which one will you choose?
選びなさいよ！
Choose already!
そらさん、キアラさん、あずきさん、ネリッサ、クロニー、そしてイマジナリーお姉さん...
Sora-san, Kiara-san, AZKi-san, Nerissa, Kronii, and my imaginary big sister...
ど、ど、どうしよう...
W-W-What should I do...
すみませんでしたーー！！
I'm so sorry!!!
ピッピッピッとBOSS待ちD-C-D-C神聖神聖
Pi-pi-pi, waiting for the BOSS, D-C-D-C, divine divine,
乗ってくってく脳内満ちてく
riding it, filling up my brain,
ダメダメダメダメダメ喰らっちゃう　俺の俺の俺の俺の...
no, no, no, no, I'll take a hit, my, my, my, my...
おっきい！
BIG ONE!
越して越してもっと越して越してちょっと越して越して
Cross over, cross over, cross over more, cross over a little, cross over,
越して越してA-B-C-D-E-F-Gッツ
cross over, cross over, A-B-C-D-E-F-G-tsu!
立てて引いてちょっと引いてやっぱ危険ピーピー
Set it up, pull back, pull back a little, after all it's dangerous, pee-pee!
したいしたいとしごろ　おれそとそらその
It's the age of wanting to do it, me, outside, sky, that one...
ちょっとだけ　ねえちょっとだけ
Just a little, hey, just a little,
見せてちょっとだけ　ほら
show me just a little, come on!
ちょっと男子！
Hey, you boys!
ちょっとだけ　ねえちょっとだけ
Just a little, hey, just a little,
見せてちょっとだけ
show me just a little!
あとは何やってる？
What else are you doing?
何やってるでござるかー！
What are you doing degozaru!
息を合わせて
Synchronize our breathing...
せーの、せーの、せーの
One, two, one, two...
はい！
Yes!
手を合わせてください！
Please put your hands together!
はい！みんな元気にいただきます！
Yes! Everyone, let's eat!
行きます！
Here I go!
さようなら... / うそー？！
Goodbye... / No way?!
ちょっと待って！ラプラス先生！皆さん！
Wait a minute! Laplus-sensei! Everyone!
おピンクです！
O-pink!
元気すぎるだろ...
She's way too energetic...
インスタントバズ祭り 青春 青春
Instant buzz festival, youth, youth
乗ってってちゅどーんの波
Ride the chudoon wave
だいだい大好きに中々
I really, really like you, but...
言えないよ胸が苦しくなっちゃう
I can't say it, my chest hurts...
君の君の君の君のターゲット
Your your your your target!
見せて見せて もっと見せて見せて ちょっと見せて見せて見せて A B C D E F G
Show me, show me, show me more, show me a little, show me, show me, A B C D E F G
ちょっと我慢ちょっと我慢 やっぱ我慢できない
Wait a bit, hold on, I really can't hold back anymore!
ちゅしてちゅしてちゅーにゅー
Kiss me, kiss me, inject it
外はココアパウダー
The outside is cocoa powder
C-U-T-E, Y-U-K-I-C-H-I!
これに勝つの負けるの？大丈夫そう？
Are we going to win or lose this? Are you going to be okay?
あ、最後までね！お疲れ様です！
Ah, until the end! Thank you for your hard work!
お疲れ様。お疲れ様です！
Thank you for your hard work. Thank you for your hard work!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
マジでいろはすビジネスで良かった〜...
Seriously, I'm glad Irohas is just business...
義務、義務。
Duty, duty.
バイバイ！じゃあね、帰るね。
Bye-bye! See ya, I'm heading home.
どうしたんですか？
What's wrong?
ねえねえ！プロデューサーの好みってどんな人なん？
Hey, hey! What kind of person is your type, Producer?
え〜...
Well...
ほら、ホロライブっていろんな人いるじゃん？
You know, Hololive has all kinds of people, right?
しゅびびゅわ〜、すぅの充電足りてるー？水宮すぅだよー！
Shubibyuwa~ Is Su's charge enough? I'm Mizumiya Su!
わっしょーい！ホロライブの清楚担当！みんなのアイドル、夏色まつりでーす！
Wasshoi! In charge of Hololive's purity! Everyone's idol, Natsuiro Matsuri!
みなさん、待ったかね〜。holoXの女幹部、鷹嶺ルイと申します〜！
Did everyone wait~? I'm holoX's female executive, Takane Lui~!
はーい、みなさま〜、こんらみ〜。ホロライブ5期生の顔が肝臓、雪花ラミィです！
Hi, everyone~ Konlamy~ The liver of Hololive 5th Gen, Yukihana Lamy!
Good evening! My cute students, ちょこーん！
Good evening! My cute students, Chokoon!
ホロライブ2期生、悪魔のバーチャル保健医、癒月ちょこでーす！ちょこーん！
Hololive 2nd Gen, devil virtual school nurse, Yuzuki Choko! Chokoon!
Ahoy! ホロライブ3期生、宝鐘海賊団船長の宝鐘マリンですぅー！
Ahoy! Hololive 3rd Gen, Houshou Pirate Captain Houshou Marin!
みなさんとても魅力的なですよ？
Everyone is very attractive, you know?
いやいや、そういうんじゃないでしょ。
No, no, that's not what I mean.
いやぁ、仕事ですからね。ホロライブの方で…とかはないですよ。
Well, it's just work. I don't feel that way towards anyone in Hololive...
ふーん...
Hmm...
ただ、最近の趣味といえば…
But if we're talking about recent hobbies...
******
[Muffled bleep]
え...
Huh...
いや... それは... さすがに... すごい趣味してるな...
Well... That's... as expected... a really wild hobby...
この人に言われたくないな…
I didn't want to hear that from you...
あ！こんな時間じゃん！我が輩ちょっとこの後用事あるんで、じゃ！
Ah! Look at the time! I've got something to do after this, so bye!
初めて呼んじまったぜ...
I actually called one for the first time...
やべぇ... 高かった...
Oh man... It was expensive...
でも、可愛かったから、いっか。
But she was cute, so whatever.
ジャケットとか、クリーニングしちゃった...
I even got my jacket dry-cleaned...
着ちゃった...
I put it on...
あ...
Ah...
え？
Eh?
これですか？
Is it this?
写真と違くないですか？
Doesn't it look different from the photo?
え？
Eh?
チェンジ！チェンジ！チェンジ！No, thank you!
Change! Change! Change! No, thank you!
それじゃちょっと息抜きでもしましょうかって感じで
So, thinking 'let's take a little break'
チラシの番号にTEL
I called the number on the flyer
たまたまドンピシャで気に入った娘がいたんで
Since there happened to be a girl I really liked right away
胸の大きい方をChoice
I chose the one with the big chest
髪型ショートで
With short hair,
攻めるのが得意な娘
and good at being aggressive
今からそちらへお送りいたします
We'll send her over to you right now
ドアを開けたら
When I opened the door,
別れた彼女
it was my ex-girlfriend!
おいおいこいつは痛い何の冗談だ
Whoa, whoa, this hurts, what kind of joke is this?
デリヘル呼んだら君が来た
I called the delivery health service and you came!
虚ろな目をして突っ立ってたんだ
Standing there with hollow eyes
あなたの好みのタイプになって
I became your favorite type
帰ってきましたって
and came back to you, she said
ロミジュリばりの悲劇に酔い
Drunk on a Romeo and Juliet-style tragedy
傷つきましてはとり急ぎ添い遂げよう
Since I've been hurt, let's urgently stay together till the end
街頭を見渡して大声でさあ
Looking around the streets, in a loud voice, now,
チェンジ！チェンジ！チェンジ！No, thank you!
Change! Change! Change! No, thank you!
朝の...
Morning...
あーはいはい
Ah, yes, yes...
ごきげんよう
Good day!
さあ上々
Now, in high spirits...
なかなかの おあんばいで
quite a good state!
隣の部屋
The next room...
相合傘
sharing an umbrella...
えぐいのは...
The shocking part is...
いや、もう！
Oh, jeez!
BPM190で
At 190 BPM!
細密連打
Meticulous continuous hits...
デスライフだから
because it's a tough life!
たまには年下
Sometimes a younger one...
縮みた小柄な子にしようか
Shall I choose a petite, small girl?
ドアを開けたら
When I opened the door,
「新人、バカの娘」
"A rookie, stupid girl,"
おいおい どんな
Hey, hey, what kind of...
魔法を使ったってんだよ
magic did you use?
デリヘル呼んだら君がいた
I called a delivery health service, and there you were.
うつろな目をして立ってたんだ
You were standing there with hollow eyes.
あなたの好みのタイプは全部わかっているのよって
"I know all your favorite types," you said.
制服、スク水、真夏のOL
Uniforms, school swimsuits, midsummer OLs,
浴衣、水着、日焼け、全部登場
yukatas, swimsuits, tan lines, they're all here!
オプションは頼まない
No options requested,
延長も心外
and extensions are out of the question!
いくぞー！
Here we go!
せーの！
Ready, set, go!
チェンジ！チェンジ！チェンジ！ノーサンキュー！
Change! Change! Change! No thank you!
デリヘル呼んだら君がいた
I called a delivery health service, and there you were.
うつろな目をして立ってたんだ
You were standing there with hollow eyes.
あなたの好みのタイプになって帰ってきましたって
"I've returned, having become your favorite type," you said.
思い出したくもない笑顔がトラウマとなって住みついた
That smile, which I don't even want to remember, became a trauma and settled in.
哀愁を見い出しだして 絶賛逃亡中
Seeing the sorrow, I am currently on the run.
さっ、せーの！
Now, ready, set, go!
チェンジ！チェンジ！チェンジ！ノーサンキュー！
Change! Change! Change! No thank you!
はぁ、疲れた...
Sigh, I'm tired...
寝るか... いや、寝過ごすな...
Shall I sleep? No, I shouldn't oversleep...
ふええ...
Fuee...
いや、いいんだよ、プロデューサーの好みとか！
No, I don't care about the producer's preferences!
ちょっとちょっと、ケンカしてどうしたの？
Wait, wait! Why are you fighting?
あっ、こよちゃん！聞いてよー、プロデューサーのやつが〜！
Ah, Koyo-chan! Listen to this, that producer guy...!
うんうん
Yeah, yeah.
それで、あいつがさ〜！
And then, that guy...!
そうだね〜、ラプちゃん辛かったね〜
I see~ That must have been tough, Lapu-chan~
はぁ、ここまで色んなホロメンと絡んできたけど...
Sigh, I've interacted with various Holo-members up to this point...
やっぱりこよちゃんが一番だよ！
...but Koyo-chan is definitely the best!
そうだ！今度の吾輩の生誕ライブ一緒に出ようよ！
I know! Let's perform together in my upcoming birthday live!
こよちゃんと吾輩にぴったりな曲があるんだ！
There's a song that's absolutely perfect for you and me!
ライブの出演ね！スケジュール...確認しておくね〜！
A live performance, huh? I'll... check my schedule!
ありがとー！じゃ、またステージで！
Thank you! Well, see you on stage!
（俺、このライブが終わったら...君と...）
(When this live is over... with you...)
時計のハリが12から
As the hands of the clock...
12に回るまで
...turn from 12 to 12,
頭ん中が染められていく
my head gets completely dyed in...
ぴんこすてぃっくluv
Pinkostick Luv.
すれ違ったり ふと目と目が
Just passing by each other, or our eyes meeting,
交わるだけで
is all it takes...
宙に浮いてる気分になる...
...to make me feel like I'm floating in midair.
イェー！イョー！
Yeah yo!
Sunday Monday ちゅーしてぎゅーして毎日クリンチ
Sunday Monday, kiss me, hug me, clinch everyday
射抜いてけ窮地 健気さcutey
Shoot through my dilemma, cute diligence
一途にwatch あっちそっちこっち向いてどっち
Watching single-mindedly, look this way, that way, this way, which way?
早まる鼓動のbpm 日に日に好きになるsml
My accelerating heart rate BPM, I like you more day by day, SML
わかってよなんて自分勝手 やっぱりきっぱりとびっきりのluv
Understand me, how selfish of me, a special love after all
ぴんこを君に伝えたい ぴんこーす
I want to convey Pinko to you, Pinko-su
脳内占拠レベルは最強 手付かず勉強 許して?ご愛嬌
My brain occupation level is the strongest, untouched homework, forgive me? My charm
胸のトキメキも絶頂
My heart's excitement is at its peak
待ちに待った今日 君とランデブー
Today I've been waiting for, a rendezvous with you
ご一緒
Together with you
なんて妄想ですます憂いのshow
Such delusions end in a melancholic show
こっち向いて まってまって やっぱ向いて
Look this way, wait wait, look at me after all
恥ずかしい だけど
It's embarrassing, but
こっち向いて 君の目に映った
Look this way, reflected in your eyes
自分の顔が赤い気がして
I feel like my face is turning red
目が合った
Our eyes met
手が触れた
Our hands touched
連打で
By hitting rapidly
連打だけで
Just by hitting rapidly
1と1のモメント
A one-on-one moment
ねぇだって「君のことが」
Hey, because 'about you'
この先がどうしてなの言えないの
What's next, why can't I say it?
まぶたの裏 思い浮かべて 好きだよ 好きなのねぇ
Thinking of it behind my eyelids, I like you, I like you, hey
思うだけで幸せなの ほんとはちょっと切ない
Just thinking about it makes me happy, though truthfully it's a bit painful
口を出る強がり見抜いて寂しがり
See through my bluff, I'm lonely
実はもう限界越えてんのだけど言えるはずない言えるわけない
Actually, I've already exceeded my limits, but I can't say it, I can't say it
臆病なハートに後押ししてwant me?
Pushing my cowardly heart, want me?
こっち向いて まってまって やっぱ向いて
Look this way, wait wait, look at me after all
独り占めしたいの
I want to monopolize you
こっち向いて わがままだってわかってるけど
Look this way, I know I'm being selfish, but
だってだってだってだって
But, but, but, but
目が合って 高鳴って 赤くなって保存
Our eyes meet, my heart beats fast, I turn red
百面相してるの
I'm making a hundred faces
今日だって君のせいでドキドキ忙しい
Even today, because of you, I'm busy with a pounding heart
神様お願いちょっとでいいから勇気をください
God, please, even just a little, please give me courage
「カジキマグロ」
“Swordfish”
チョー！
Cho!
プロデューサー、あぁ！！！
Producer! Aah!!!
どうしたんですか？
What's the matter?
こよちゃんにフラれたぁ〜
Koyori-chan dumped me!
フラれるとかあるんですね？"
Oh, so you can actually get dumped?
ちくしょう！！！こうなったら！！！
Damn it!!! If that's the case!!!
嫌な予感がする
I have a bad feeling about this.
誰でもいいから付き合いたいー！！
I want to go out with anyone, whoever they are!!!
そうなったらもう終わりですよ
If it comes to that, it's all over.
うるさい！吾輩は…彼女作って幸せになるんだー！！！！
Shut up! I'm... going to get a girlfriend and be happy!!!!
横画面で開始します
[Start in landscape mode]
やるぞ、緊張する。やってやるぞ。
Let's do this. I'm nervous. I can do this!
誰でもいいから付き合いたい
I want to go out with anyone, whoever they are
もう 誰でもいいから
Anymore, anyone is fine...
男の前では喋れても
Even if I can speak in front of men
女の前では喋れない
I can't speak in front of women
トラウマだらけの僕の過去
My past full of trauma
涙なしでは語れない
Can't be told without tears
どうして彼女ができないの？
Why can't I get a girlfriend?
「僕は素敵」と君は言う
“You're wonderful,” you say to me
それなら僕と付き合ってよ！
In that case, go out with me!
その苦笑いの意味はなに？
What's the meaning of that bitter smile?
誰でもいいから付き合いたい
I want to go out with anyone, whoever they are
もう 誰でもいいから
Anymore, anyone is fine...
誰でもいいから付き合いたい
I want to go out with anyone, whoever they are
もう 誰でもいいから
Anymore, anyone is fine...
誰でもいいから付き合いたい
I want to go out with anyone, whoever they are
もう 誰でもいいから
Anymore, anyone is fine...
なんで？なんでだよ〜！！！
Why? Why is this happening?!!!
全員からフラれたぁ〜〜〜！！！
Everyone dumped me~~~!!!
うーん、このライブ、大丈夫かな
Hmm, is this live show going to be okay?
くそ、もうこうなったら！
Damn it, if that's the case!
ええ！？なんですかそれ！
Eh!? What is that?!
この封印を…解放してやるぅ！！！"
I'll... release this seal!!!
俺の聖植を…爆裂させてやるぅ！！！うおーーー！！！
I'll make my holy plants... explode!!! Uooooh!!!
お、おしまいだこのライブは…もはやライブなのかも怪しい所…
I-It's all over for this live show... At this point, it's doubtful if it's even a live show...
横画面で開始します
[Start in landscape mode]
なんていうか大きな声で言うことではないかもしれませんが
How should I put it... It might not be something to say out loud, but...
男女に備わったあれとそれ
that and this that men and women are equipped with,
正と乱とのいわばあれとそれ
or rather, this and that of purity and chaos.
そんなこんなで起こるhappening
A happening that occurs because of all this,
あっというまに僕のending
and in the blink of an eye, my ending.
あやまって悩んで困ってしまって
Apologizing, worrying, getting troubled,
どうしよってなにもできない無情
wondering what to do, I can do nothing—how heartless.
0.02mmの壁がすげーもどかしくなって
The 0.02mm wall gets incredibly frustrating,
真っ赤なmy sunshine
my crimson sunshine.
すぐに入れたくなるのは君の性
Wanting to put it in right away is your nature.
いいじゃーんとかそんな気分で
Accepting it with a 'why not' kind of mood,
迎えた君と僕そんなヘブンで
you and I welcomed it in such a heaven.
あ、しまったって思ったって
Even if I think, 'Oh, crap!'
もう遅い
It's already too late.
Upside inside out. I defend you.
甘噛み youの髪
Nibbling on your hair,
いっさいがっさいは
absolutely everything,
愛で返事
I'll reply with love.
I'm coming. You're coming.
甘噛み youの髪
Nibbling on your hair,
いっさいがっさいは
absolutely everything,
愛で返事
I'll reply with love.
I'm coming. You're coming.
待って これって僕のせい？
Wait, is this my fault?
生でいいよって言った君のせい？
Is it your fault for saying it's fine raw?
そして5分で終わるテストって
And a test that finishes in five minutes,
シンピョウセイ欠けるもんだって
its credibility is highly doubtful.
しっかり刻まれた十字架に
Onto the deeply engraved cross,
はりつけられた僕は切り捨てに
crucified, I am cast aside.
なったって無理ってわかっているって
Even if it's like this, I know it's impossible,
どうしよってなにもできない
wondering what to do, I can do nothing.
0.02mmの壁がすげー悩ましくなって
The 0.02mm wall gets incredibly seductive,
真っ青なmy sunshine
my pale blue sunshine.
すぐに入れたくなるのは僕の性
Wanting to put it in right away is my nature.
大丈夫とかそんな気分で
With a 'it'll be fine' kind of mood,
甲斐性もないこんな身分で
in this worthless social standing of mine,
泣いたって怒ったって
whether I cry or get angry,
後の祭り
it's too late now.
Maximum insert なう。
Maximum insert now.
Are you ready?
愛撫ハニー 指噛み
Caressing, honey, biting your finger,
聖槍爆裂ボーイ
Holy Lance Explosion Boy!
愛がfeeling. I've honey. You be coming.
Love is feeling. I've honey. You be coming.
愛撫ハニー 指噛み
Caressing, honey, biting your finger,
聖槍爆裂ボーイ
Holy Lance Explosion Boy!
愛がfeeling. I've honey. You be coming.
Love is feeling. I've honey. You be coming.
遠い夏の思い出
A distant summer memory...
君の長い髪が揺れる
your long hair swaying...
待って これって僕のせい？
Wait, is this my fault?
中に出してって言った君のせい？
Is it your fault for telling me to release it inside?
そして5分で終わるテストって
And a test that finishes in five minutes,Convert to dualism.
絶対的二元論だって
is an absolute dualism.
十月十日ばかりの運命を
The destiny of ten months and ten days,
支配している僕は神様に
controlling it, I cannot become...
なれないって無理ってわかって保存する
...a god, I know it's impossible.
結局何も解決してない
In the end, nothing has been resolved.
0.02mmの壁がすげーもどかしくなって
The 0.02mm wall gets incredibly frustrating,
真っ白なmy sunshine
my pure white sunshine.
すぐに入れたくなるのは君のせい
Wanting to put it in right away is your fault.
いいじゃーんとかそんな気分で
Accepting it with a 'why not' kind of mood,
迎えた君と僕そんなヘブンで
you and I welcomed it in such a heaven.
あ、しまったって思ったって
Even if I think, 'Oh, crap!'
もう遅い
It's already too late.
Upside inside out. I defend you.
甘噛み youの髪
Nibbling on your hair,
いっさいがっさいは
absolutely everything,
愛で返事
I'll reply with love.
I'm coming. You're coming.
甘噛み youの髪
Nibbling on your hair,
いっさいがっさいは
absolutely everything,
愛で返事
I'll reply with love.
I'm coming. You're coming.
Maximum insert なう。
Maximum insert now.
Are you ready?
愛撫ハニー 指噛み
Caressing, honey, biting your finger,
聖槍爆裂ボーイ
Holy Lance Explosion Boy!
愛がfeeling. I've honey. You be coming.
Love is feeling. I've honey. You be coming.
愛撫ハニー 指噛み
Caressing, honey, biting your finger,
聖槍爆裂ボーイ
Holy Lance Explosion Boy!
愛がfeeling. I've honey. You be coming.
Love is feeling. I've honey. You be coming.
（プロデューサー）いやあ、まさか、聖槍でライブ会場壊しちゃうなんて
(Producer) Wow, I can't believe the Holy Lance actually destroyed the live venue...
「つい…力を解放してしまった…」
"I ended up... releasing my power..."
「それにしても、みんなど酷くない？吾輩をふるなんて…」
"Even so, isn't everyone way too cruel? Rejecting me like that..."
「もうやってらんないよ〜」
"I can't do this anymore!"
（プロデューサー）ここはあの手を使うしかない
(Producer) I have no choice but to use *that* trick here.
（プロデューサー）ラプラスさん、実は、あの方に来ていただきます！
(Producer) La+-san, actually, we've invited *that person* to come!
「あの方？」
"That person?"
「ラプくん？どうしたのー？」
"Rapu-kun? What's wrong?"
「うわっ！？あ、あ、あじゅ姉！？まさか、吾輩のために来てくれたの？？？？」
"Whoa!? A-A-Aju-nee!? Did you... actually come here for me????"
「当然だよー！だって今日は、ラプくんの誕生日でしょ？」
"Of course! Because today is your birthday, right, Rapu-kun?"
「あ、やばい、吾輩今日が命日かもしれん…」
"Ah, oh no, today might be the anniversary of my death..."
「お誕生日おめでとう！プレゼントは何がいいのかな〜？」
"Happy birthday! I wonder what you'd like for a present?"
「え！プレゼントってなんでももらえるの？！」
"Eh! Can I get anything as a present?!"
「あじゅがあげられるものなら何でも大丈夫ゾ☆」
"As long as it's something Aju can give you, anything is fine☆"
「えー！！えええ！じゃあ」
"Eh!! Really! Then..."
「え？今なんて言ったの？変な音で聞こえなかった！」
note: BLEEP sound is between 04:32 and 04:35, Azusa speaks from 04:35 to 04:40.
"Eh? What did you just say? I couldn't hear over that weird sound!"
「あれ？」
"Huh?"
「なんだこれー！届かないぞ吾輩の願いが！」
note: Another BLEEP sound is between 04:42 and 04:44, La+ speaks from 04:44 to 04:48.
"What is this! My wish isn't getting through!"
（プロデューサー）あぶない…危うく配信できないところだった…
(Producer) That was close... It almost became unable to be broadcasted...
「邪魔するなプロデューサーーー！！！！！」
"Don't get in my way, Producer!!!!!"
「なんか色々大変そうだから…今日はこの辺で帰るね！今日は本当におめでとー！ラプくん、また遊ぼうね〜」
"It seems like a lot is going on, so... I'll head home for today! Happy birthday once again! Let's hang out again, Rapu-kun~"
今日は本当におめでと～！ラプくん、また遊ぼうね～
Congratulations on today! Lap-kun, let's hang out again~
あ、あじゅねぇ！あじゅねぇえええ！！！
Ah, Aju-nee! Aju-neee!!!
え、はい、はい、分かりました！
Uh, yes, yes, I understand!
ラプラスさん！新曲オーディションですって！
Laplus-san! It's an audition for a new song!
どゆこと！？
What do you mean?!
新曲だけのオーディション大会があって、そこで優勝したら、大型コラボですって！
There's an audition tournament for new songs, and if you win, you get a major collaboration!
今すぐ曲準備します！
I'll prepare the song right away!
ダンスレッスンいれますね！
I'll schedule a dance lesson!
今から新曲？ダンスレッスン？ま、間に合うのそれ？もうライブまでちょっとしかないよ？
A new song starting now? Dance lessons? W-Will we make it? There's barely any time left until the live concert!
間に合わせてください！もしオーディションに合格したら、大型コラボなんです！！
Please make it in time! If you pass the audition, it's a major collaboration!!
えー！我輩もう疲れたんですけど！！大型コラボってなんなの！？
What?! But I'm already exhausted!! What even is this major collaboration?!
それはまだ、秘密です。
That is still a secret.
なんでだよおお！！！
Why?! Come on!!!
…はぁ、はぁ、はぁ、はぁ、はぁ、体力ないって言ってるのに、走り込み…？
...*pant*, *pant*, *pant*, *pant*, *pant*... I told you I have no stamina, so why running...?
だからこその走り込みです！
That is exactly why you're running!
…はぁ、この筋トレ、本当に意味あるの？
...*sigh*, is this muscle training really necessary?
…だっ、はぁ、あああ…
...*pant*, *gasp*, aaa...
よし！良い感じだ！
Alright! Looking good!
ラプラスさん！本番前に行きましょう！あの方の元へ！
Laplus-san! Let's go before the show! To that person's place!
あ、あの方！？あー…よし！行こう！！
T-That person?! Ah... alright! Let's go!!
チョコ先生！！！
Choco-sensei!!!
あら、いらっしゃい、ラプちゃん。
Oh, welcome, Lapu-chan.
どれにするの？
Which one will you choose?
ん～、悩んじゃうよねぇ。
Hmm, it's hard to decide, isn't it?
わかる、わかる。
I know, I know.
答えは一つじゃないからねぇ。
Because there isn't just one right answer.
ラプちゃん、真剣に考えてるわねぇ。
Lapu-chan, thinking so seriously about it.
え？全部ちゃんと見たいの？
Eh? You want to take a proper look at all of them?
じゃあ、皆さんお待ちかねの、グッズ情報よ！ラプちゃん！
Then, here is the merchandise information everyone's been waiting for! Lapu-chan!
はい！はいはいはい！
Yes! Yes yes yes!
ラプラス・ダークネス、誕生日記念2026グッズ！順番に紹介していきます！
Laplus Darkness's Birthday Celebration 2026 Merchandise! We'll introduce them one by one!
じゃん！まずはこちら！カードアルバム！
Ta-da! First up is this! The Card Album!
特典のチェキ風ブロマイドカードとか、ホロカとかを収納できるアルバムです！
It's an album where you can store special instax-style photo cards, Holoka cards, and more!
えっと、めっちゃ久しぶりに三輪先生が…
And, after a really long time, Miwa-sensei...
我輩のママね、クロネママが描き下ろしてくれました、イラスト！
My illustrator mama, Kurone-mama, has drawn a new illustration for this!
めっちゃ可愛い！！！
That's so cute!!!
はい、でしょ？
Right?
このアルバムをギュッてしてるのがまたいいよね。
The way you're hugging this album is so nice.
そう、そうでしょ？これもちゃんと、あのアルバムをギュッとしてるんですよ、売ってるやつを。
Exactly, right? This illustration actually shows me hugging the album that is on sale.
じゃあ、これ買ったら、ラプちゃんがギュッとしたアルバムが手に入るってこと？
So if someone buys this, they get the album that you hugged?
え？！それは、あの、商品法…景表法的に…
Eh?! Well, that might violate, uh, product laws... or the Premiums and Representations Act...
二つ目はこちら！興奮ボイスキーホルダー！
The second item is this! The Excited Voice Keyholder!
毎回おなじみの、録り下ろしボイスが6種類入ったキーホルダーです！
It's the usual keyholder containing 6 newly recorded voices!
押すと声が出ます、いつも通り。今回も白こ先…白こ先生の描き下ろしです！
You can press it to play the voices as always. This time, it's also drawn by Shiroko-sensei!
メロメロな表情をしたオリジナルのデフォルメ姿です。
It features an original chibi-style illustration with a love-struck face.
押すと声が出る。
Pressing it plays a voice.
はい。
Yes.
えー、どこを押すのかな？
Hmm, I wonder where we should press?
え、ど…ちょっと、どこを…み、三つ目は！三つ目はこちら！
Wait, wha... hold on, where are you... T-The third! The third item is this!
ばぶラプラスぬいぐるみです！
The Baby Laplus Plushie!
おしゃぶりを…おしゃぶりをくわえて、ベビーウェアを着て寝ている我輩のぬいぐるみでございます。
It's a plushie of me sucking on a pacifier, wearing baby clothes, and sleeping.
え、めっちゃ可愛い！
Oh, that's incredibly cute!
我輩もギュッてしたい！
I want to hug you tight too!
チョコ先生、そ、それは…
Choco-sensei, th-that is...
ギュッてしたい！
I want to hug you!
いつでも…いつでも、あ、あ、あああ！やめてください！本当に！
A-Anytime... anytime... Ah, ah, aaa! Please stop! Seriously!
もうまずいまずい、四つ目はこちら！
This is bad, this is bad! The fourth item is this!
ばぶラプラスぬいぐるみを包めるハンカチです！
A handkerchief that can wrap the Baby Laplus Plushie!
さっきのぬいぐるみを包めて、あとは普通にハンカチとしても使えます。
You can wrap the plushie I just showed you, and you can also use it as a normal handkerchief.
おくるみとして使えるってことね。
So it can be used as a swaddling blanket.
そうです。可愛い！デカ、デカいです、これ。これくらいしかないです、大きさ。
Yes. It's cute! It's big, actually quite big. Its size is about this much.
そして最後に！フルセット購入特典として、三輪クロネママ描き下ろしのチェキ風ブロマイドカードがついてきます！
And finally! As a full set purchase bonus, you'll get an instax-style photo card drawn by Miwa Kurone-mama!
はい、数量限定バージョンは、我輩の直筆サインと複製メッセージが入ってます！
Yes! The limited-quantity version includes my hand-written signature and a printed message!
通常バージョンは、箔押しの複製サインとメッセージが入っているよ。
The regular version includes a foil-stamped printed autograph and a message.
この配信のあとに販売開始だから、
Sales start after this stream, so...
みんな、よろしくねー！
...please check it out, everyone!
お願いしまーす！
Please do!
はい。以上グッズ紹介なんですけど...
Yes. That is all for the merch introduction, but...
Choco先生、ありがとうございました。
Choco-sensei, thank you very much!
ええ、こちらこそ！
No, thank you!
これからちょっとオーディションなんで、新曲の。
Actually, I have an audition next for my new song.
お、頑張って。
Oh, good luck!
頑張ります。
I will do my best!
応援してるね、ラプちゃん。頑張って！
I'll be rooting for you, Lapu-chan! Good luck!
頑張ります！ありがとうございます！
I will! Thank you so much!
頑張れー！
Good luck!
お姉さま♡ラヴコール / Now Loading
[Title: Oneesama ♡ Love Call]
あ、お姉さま！
Ah, Big Sister!
あの、今日ライブなのに、我が輩お風呂入ってないんですけど、
Um, even though we have a concert today, I haven't taken a bath yet...
お願いがあって、あの...
But I have a request, um...
耳なめてほしいです！
I want you to lick my ears!
お姉さま♡ ああ お姉さま♡
Big Sister♡ Ah, Big Sister♡
すーはー すーはー お姉さま♡
Sniff, sniff, sniff, sniff, Big Sister♡
お姉さま♡ ああ お姉さま♡
Big Sister♡ Ah, Big Sister♡
お・ね・え・さ・ま～～～！
B-i-g S-i-s-t-e-r~~~!
世の中のお姉さまに捧ぐ
Dedicated to all the big sisters in the world!
あ、お姉さま♡ ああお姉さま♡
Ah, Big Sister♡ Ah, Big Sister♡
起きたら耳元で囁いて
Whisper in my ear when you wake up
あ、お姉さま♡ ああお姉さま♡
Ah, Big Sister♡ Ah, Big Sister♡
目元に滴るその汗を
The sweat dripping from around your eyes...
我が輩のお紅茶に入れて ゴックンゴックンしたいイww
...I want to put it in my tea and gulp it down! lol
ツノのツノのツノ掴んでちょうだい
Grab my horns, horns, horns
ハンドル代わりにオーオーオー！
And use them like handlebars, oh oh oh!
あ、あ、お姉さまと、
A- Ah, Big Sister and...
視聴者の、助けて！
...viewers, save me!
こんな歌ライブで歌ってごめんなさい！
I'm sorry for singing this kind of song at a live!
あ、お仕置き！お仕置きしてください！
Ah, punishment! Please punish me!
しっぽから手つっこんでガタガタ揺らしてくださいツノを！
Stick your hand in my tail and shake my horns vigorously!
あ、お姉さま、今日、見入りでした...
Ah, Big Sister, it was a packed house today...
盛り上がってきましたね！
It's getting exciting, isn't it!
えっ、お姉さま？お姉さまちゃん？あ、お姉さま！
Eh, Big Sister? Big Sister-chan? Ah, Big Sister!
あ、お世話になっております！
Ah, thank you for always taking care of me!
ありがたや やさやさ ありがたやーほい
Thankful, thankful, thankful, yay!
おいでなすって お姉さま
Come on over, Big Sister!
雑魚 雑魚 と言ってください
Please call me trash, trash!
残さず飲み込むゾ
I'll swallow it all up!
愛のムチムチ 愛のムチ
Whip of love, plump, whip of love!
お願いなぶって、お姉さま！
Please tease me, Big Sister!
キモくてごめんなさい！
I'm sorry for being gross!
ありのままでキャストオフ！
Cast off, just as you are!
お姉さま♡ ああ お姉さま♡
Big Sister♡ Ah, Big Sister♡
すーはー すーはー お姉さま♡
Sniff, sniff, sniff, sniff, Big Sister♡
お姉さま♡ ああ お姉さま♡
Big Sister♡ Ah, Big Sister♡
お・ね・え・さ・ま～～～！
B-i-g S-i-s-t-e-r~~~!
刮目せよ！ YMDはもう古い！
Feast your eyes! YMD is outdated!
時代はYSOだ！
Now is the era of YSO!
YSOとは何か？
What does YSO stand for?
そう！
That's right!
やたらセクシーなお姉さま！
Extremely sexy Big Sisters!
YSO! YSO! YSO!
YSO! YSO! YSO! YSO!
YY YY YSO
お姉さま！ お姉さま！
Big Sister! Big Sister!
やたらセクシーなお姉さま！
Extremely sexy Big Sisters!
ほんわか ドジっ子 姉御肌
Gentle, clumsy, big-sisterly type...
クーデレ ツンデレ 小悪魔系
...cool-and-sweet, tsundere, little devil type...
いろんなお姉がいるけれど
...there are many kinds of big sisters, but...
あらあらウフフが優勝ですww
...the "Ara ara, ufufu" one is the absolute winner! lol
もち肌！ （ぷにぷに）
Smooth skin! (Squishy)
太もも！ （スリスリ）
Thighs! (Rubbing)
ギューして！ （むにむに）
Hug me! (Squeeze)
居なけりゃ無理無理イイイ！
Without them, it's impossible, impossible!
ああん、お姉さまがいない世界なんて
Ah, a world without Big Sisters...
耐えられないでちゅううう！！！！
...I can't endure it, boohoo!!!!
そうして、吾輩は赤ちゃんになった。
And so, I became a baby.
なぜなぜ、よしよしされる幸せな世界。
A happy world of being pampered and comforted.
今日もまた、お姉さまの太ももに顔を埋め
Today again, I bury my face in Big Sister's thighs...
歪み（よだれ）を垂らす。これが、人生なのだ。
...and drool. This is indeed life.
キモくたらしく美しく！
Creepily, droolingly, and beautifully!
おいでって言って、お姉さま！
Tell me to come here, Big Sister!
ダコダコしてください
Please say "hug me, hug me"!
本能が剥き出しレゾ！
Our instincts are fully exposed!
足のむちむち 胸のむちむち
Plump legs, plump chest!
お触りします！ お姉さま！
I'm going to touch you! Big Sister!
全裸でごめんなさい！
I'm sorry for being completely naked!
ありのままでキャストオフ！
Cast off, just as you are!
愛してます、お姉さま♡
I love you, Big Sister♡
お姉さま♡ ああ お姉さま♡
Big Sister♡ Ah, Big Sister♡
すーはー すーはー お姉さま♡
Sniff, sniff, sniff, sniff, Big Sister♡
お姉さま♡ ああ お姉さま♡
Big Sister♡ Ah, Big Sister♡
やたらセクシーなお姉さま！
Extremely sexy Big Sisters!
お姉さま♡ ああ お姉さま♡
Big Sister♡ Ah, Big Sister♡
すーはー すーはー お姉さま♡
Sniff, sniff, sniff, sniff, Big Sister♡
お姉さま♡ ああ お姉さま♡
Big Sister♡ Ah, Big Sister♡
お・ね・え・さ・ま～～～！
B-i-g S-i-s-t-e-r~~~!
あ... ばぶぅ
Ah... babu...
ということで、
And with that,
新曲を披露させていただきました。
I've performed my new song for you.
タイトルは、お姉様...
The title is... "Oneesama..."
お姉様、ラヴコールです！
"Oneesama Love Call"!
ちゃんと、お姉様のあとにハートがつくやつです。
It's the one with a heart right after "Oneesama".
ビートまりおさんと、まらしぃさんに作ってもらいました！
It was made for me by Beat Mario-san and Marasy-san!
依頼した時は、なんか...
When I requested it...
「最近のラプラスさんを見てたらなんか楽しく作れました」みたいな言ってくれました。
They told me, "We had fun making it after watching the recent Laplus-san"!
とんでもない曲になっちゃったぜ！
It turned out to be an incredible song!
収録のときも、あ、これはあとでリリースされるんですけど、
During the recording too—ah, this will be released later, but...
収録するときもね、なんか...
during the recording, they were like...
「もっとキモく！もっとうちなるお姉様への思いを込めながら歌ってください」とか言われて、
"Be creepier! Sing while putting more of your inner feelings for your sister into it!"
あんなディレクションは初めてでした。
I've never received that kind of direction before.
そんな曲がこのあと、MVがね、
The music video for that song...
私のこのチャンネルでプレミア公開されますよ！
will premiere right after this on my channel!
そして、まぁ今日25日なんですけど、
And, well, today is the 25th...
明日26日に日付が変わった瞬間にこの曲がリリースされてしまいます！
but the moment the date changes to tomorrow, the 26th, this song will be released!
さらに、なんと！まぁこれはね、サムネにもね、釣りみたいな感じで重大告知みたいな感じで書いたんですけど、
Furthermore, believe it or not! Well, I put "Major Announcement" on the thumbnail as clickbait...
なんと、ついに、私ラプラス・ダークネス、一人で初めてのアルバムが発売されるぜ！イェーイ！
but finally, I, Laplus Darkness, will be releasing my very first solo album! Yay!
いや、なんか1年に1曲しかオリジナル曲出さなかったのに、
I mean, I used to only release one original song a year...
去年狂ったようにオリ曲出して、今年も出して、
but last year I released them like crazy, and this year too...
アルバムが出せるようになるなんてね、感慨深いものでございます。
To think I'd be able to release an album... It really fills me with deep emotion.
精度、なんと今回は2種類出るんだけど、
And surprisingly, there will be two versions released this time.
1つ目がね、ラプラス・ダークネス 1st Album『ラブ様アーティスト化計画』高いやつ！
The first is Laplus Darkness 1st Album "Laf-sama Artist-ification Project"—the expensive one!
ということで、高いやつです。
So, yes, the expensive version.
でもう1つが、『ラブ様アーティスト化計画』安いやつ！
And the other is "Laf-sama Artist-ification Project"—the cheap one!
ということで、お金を...
So, for those who...
持っている、大きいお友達用のアルバムと、
have money, the album for "big friends"...
まあお小遣い、ママにお願いしようかな、ママ買って、みたいなのでお願いできそうな値段の、
and one at a price where you could ask, "Hey Mom, can you buy this for me?"...
まあホロライブで出てるアルバムだと一番安いんじゃない？っていうくらい安いやつ。
probably the cheapest album released in Hololive—the cheap version!
の2種類があるよ！
Those are the two versions available!
この配信のあとから、ホロライブ公式ショップで予約開始だから、みんな予約してね！
Pre-orders start on the official Hololive shop right after this stream, so make sure to pre-order!
詳しくはホームページをチェック！
Check the website for details!
さっき披露した新曲も、もちろんアルバムに入るぜ！
The new song I performed earlier will, of course, be in the album too!
さあ、新曲オーディションは果たした。
Well, I've completed the new song audition.
なんかあとは結果待つだけなんで、おやすみバイバイ！
Now I just have to wait for the results. Goodnight, bye-bye!
お疲れ！
Good job!
優勝したらね、褒美って言ってたんだっけな。なんだろうな〜。
They said there'd be a reward if I won. I wonder what it is...
やりましたね！優勝ですよ！
We did it! You won!
さすがにレッスンとか急すぎたって〜。もうへとへと〜。
Honestly, lessons and stuff were way too sudden... I'm completely exhausted.
...はい、分かりました！
...Yes, understood!
ラプラスさん...
Laplus-san...
お？
Huh?
今すぐいきますよ！大型コラボの現場へ！！！
We're going right now! To the big collaboration venue!!!
え？なに？え、なにになに？どこ行くの〜？？？
Eh? What? Wait, what? Where are we going???
みんな、
Everyone,
こんばんは！
good evening!
来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming!
短い時間だけど、一緒に楽しもうね！
It's only for a short time, but let's have fun together!
今日は、特別なゲストが来てくれています！
Today, we have a very special guest with us!
ホロライブの、ラプラス・ダークネスさんです！
From Hololive, it's Laplus Darkness-san!
え？何？何？みなさん、こんにちは。
Eh? What? What? Hello everyone!
うわ、本当に、本当にりなみお姉...
Wow, it's really, really Rinami-onee...
これ、本当にりなみさんですか？
Is this... Is this really Rinami-san?
はい！初めまして！
Yes! Nice to meet you!
今日はご一緒できて光栄です！ / あ、はい！
I'm honored to be with you today! / Ah, yes!
なんて呼んだらいいですか？
What should I call you?
あ、あの、あの敬語やめてください。あの、吾輩のことは...
Ah, um, please stop using polite language. Um, about me...
あの、ラプ...ラプ君って呼んでください。
Um, please call me Lap-kun.
吾輩も、りなみお姉さんって呼んでもいいですか？
Can I call you Rinami-oneesan too?
もちろん！
Of course!
りなみお姉さんって呼んでくれると嬉しいな、ラプ君！
I'd be happy if you call me Rinami-oneesan, Lap-kun!
りなみお姉さん... / はい！
Rinami-oneesan... / Yes!
ラプ君！ / はい！
Lap-kun! / Yes!
今日は私の曲を披露させてもらうんだけど...
Today I'm going to perform my song,
ラプ君も会場を盛り上げるために、ちょっとだけ一緒に参加してくれるんだよね？
and Lap-kun, you're going to join in a bit to help pump up the venue, right?
はい、あの、恐縮です。あの、本当はちょっとこんな近くで見れるだけでも、嬉しいんですけど...
Yes, um, I'm humbled. Actually, I'm just happy to be able to watch from this close, but...
微力ながら、参加させていただきます！
though of little help, I will participate!
うん！一緒に共演できて嬉しいよ！
Yeah! I'm happy we can perform together!
素敵なライブになるといいね！
I hope it turns out to be a wonderful live concert!
はい！
Yes!
それじゃあ、早速一曲、披露させてもらおうかな？
Then, shall I perform a song right away?
ラプ君、準備はいい？
Lap-kun, are you ready?
あ、はい！もちろん、あの、行きます、準備します、あ、行きます！
Ah, yes! Of course, um, here I go, I'll get ready, ah, here I go!
みんなも一緒に楽しもうね！
Let's all have fun together!
それでは一曲目、聴いてください！
Now, please listen to the first song!
I know 愛のボーダー
I know, love's border
今日は少しだけ 飛び越えてみちゃおっか
Shall we try jumping over it just a little bit today?
全然ハジマンナイ物語を見ているような気分
It feels like I'm watching a story that hasn't started at all
鈍感な君にお知らせします
I'll let you know, you're oblivious
このままいけばエンドロールで you＝エキストラA
If we keep going like this, you'll be 'Extra A' in the end credits
すぐ逸らすその目も 待てど出ないロマンスの芽も
That gaze that looks away, and the bud of romance that won't sprout no matter how long I wait
「ねえねえ、ちょっとおでこ貸して♪」でラブもデコっちゃう？
'Hey, hey, lend me your forehead for a bit ♪' Want to decorate our love with that?
急な「ぎゅっ」でキュンもcute 私のcue受け取ってよ
Sudden 'tight squeeze', the heart-throb is cute too, please accept my cue
超えてく展開見てみたいの
I want to see a development that goes beyond this
私からモーションじゃ王道すぎるでしょ？
If I'm the one who makes a move, it's too cliché, right?
36℃ウブな君にcaution！
36°C, caution for you, you naive boy!
もうちょい私にお熱をあげて欲しいのです
I want you to be a little more passionate about me
君にとって私は一体何なの？
What on earth am I to you?
はい、ど～ぞ ここからは君の番
Yes, go ahead, from here on, it's your turn
上手く言おうとなんてしないで
Don't try to say it perfectly
ちょっと不自然くらいじゃなきゃ
If it's not a little bit unnatural
恋なんてそう始まりようがないもの
Love wouldn't have a way to start like that
かくかくしかじか... つまりはlove song
This and that... in short, it's a love song
出来不出来は横に置いて耽溺を希望
Setting aside whether it's good or bad, I'm hoping to be addicted
ちょっとhighな熱いloveにうなされてみない？
Want to try being possessed by a slightly high, hot love?
キホンのキホン 恋の三大 cha cha cha
Basic of the basics, the three major cha-cha-chas of love
chance・chase・challenge
chance, chase, challenge
用のないメッセージ さりげないタッチ
Useless messages, casual touches
翻訳すればすべてがつまりラビュー
When translated, everything is, in short, love-u
頭で考えずに脊髄反射で応えて
Don't think with your head, respond with a spinal reflex
no noだけじゃ能がないよ
Just 'no, no' is no good
そうよ あとちょっと もう一歩
Yes, just a little more, one more step
3・2・1で
At 3, 2, 1
やればできる子 素直でよろしい
You're a kid who can do it if you try, I like you being honest
36℃ニブい君にcaution！
36°C, caution for you, you dull boy!
「どうせ・だって・でもでも」なんて3Dを抜け出して
Break out of the 3D 'anyway, because, but, but' stuff
異次元的ステキをいっぱい感じて
Feel lots of otherworldly wonderful things
はい、ど～ぞ ここからは君の番
Yes, go ahead, from here on, it's your turn
「違うかも...」なんて構えないで
Don't get defensive thinking 'Maybe I'm wrong...'
ちょっとくらいの勘違いがなきゃ
If there isn't a little bit of misunderstanding
恋なんてそう始まりようがないもの
Love wouldn't have a way to start like that
ラプ君、お誕生日おめでとう！
Lap-kun, happy birthday!
えっ！？あ、ありがとうございます！
Eh!? Th-Thank you very much!
一緒に！クラップ！
Together! Clap!
はい、はい、はい、はい！
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
「ねえねえ、ちょっとおでこ貸して♪」でラブもデコっちゃう？
'Hey, hey, lend me your forehead for a bit ♪' Want to decorate our love with that?
急な「ぎゅっ」でキュンもcute 私のcue受け取ってよ
Sudden 'tight squeeze', the heart-throb is cute too, please accept my cue
予感に身を委ねてみたいの
I want to entrust my body to a premonition
私からモーションじゃ王道すぎるでしょ？
If I'm the one who makes a move, it's too cliché, right?
３６度とウブな 君にのぼせちゃう
I'm getting dizzy over 36 degrees and your innocence.
もうちょい私にお熱をあげてほしいのです
I want you to give me a little more of your heat.
余裕に見えて 私もいっぱいいっぱいで本地
Though I look relaxed, I'm actually overwhelmed.
はい勝負！本音を打ち明けちゃう
It's a showdown! I'll reveal my true feelings.
完璧な おねだりだって
Even with perfect begging,
ちょっとくらいの隙がなくちゃ
there needs to be at least a little opening.
好きになんて なれるはずがないものでしょ
Otherwise, there's no way you can fall for me, right?
だから君を 待ち伏せています
That's why I'm waiting in ambush for you.
いつだって
Anytime,
ちょっと
just a little...
甘い誘惑に連れ去られてみたい
I want to be carried away by sweet temptation.
#ラブさま大解放2026
[On-Screen: #LoveSamaGrandRelease2026]
「36℃ U・B・U」でしたー！
That was '36℃ UBU'!
どうだったかなー？
How was it?
最高でしたー！
It was awesome!
ラプくんありがとう！
Thank you, Lapu-kun!
一緒にパフォーマンスしてくれて嬉しいよ！
I'm so happy you performed with me!
は、あの、光栄で楽しかったです。
Y-Yes, um, it was an honor and so much fun.
あの、間近でそらちゃんのパフォーマンス見れて、もう光栄でした！
Getting to see Sora-chan's performance up close was such an honor!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
えっと、今日は次の曲が最後になるんだけど...
Um, the next song will be the last one today, but...
えー！早すぎます！
Eh?! That's too fast!
まだ見たいです！
I still want to watch!
うふふ、名残惜しいけど...
Ehehe, I'll miss it too, but...
次の曲はみんなにも声を出してほしいな！
For the next song, I want everyone to raise their voices!
一緒に最後まで楽しもうね！ラプくんも。
Let's have fun together until the end! You too, Lapu-kun.
も、もちろんですよ！もう声枯れるまでやります！
O-Of course! I'll do it until my voice goes hoarse!
ラプくん、喉は大事にしてね。
Lapu-kun, take care of your throat.
はい！あ、そらお姉ちゃん、
Yes! Ah, Sora-oneechan,
あの、我輩の先輩もどうしてもライブ見たいって言ってるんですけど...
um, my senior also really wants to watch the live...
呼んでいいですか？
can I invite her over?
えっ、だれだれ？
Eh, who is it?
ぜひぜひ！
Please do!
すみません、あ、お呼び出ししましょう。
Excuse me, ah, let's call her over.
おーい！
Heyyy!
よ、よろしくお願いします！
P-Please treat me well!
そら先輩、ありがとうございます！
Sora-senpai, thank you so much!
わー、みこさん！
Wow, Miko-san!
お会いできて光栄です！
It's an honor to meet you!
こ、こちらこそです！
L-Likewise!
パフォーマンス楽しみにしてます！
We're looking forward to your performance!
うん！
Yeah!
お姉ちゃん頑張っちゃうよ！
Onee-chan is gonna do her best!
か、可愛すぎる...
S-She's too cute...
それでは、次の曲聞いてください。
Now, please listen to the next song.
退屈中 熱くなり お茶いかが？
Getting hot during boredom, how about some tea?
冷静に 大人びた？
Calmly, did I grow up?
ハートは君も欲しい？
Do you want my heart too?
ご相談 チラチラと
A little consultation, peeking at me.
余裕身につけて
Acquiring some composure,
憂鬱 お相手は優等 絡まぬよう
melancholy. Your opponent is a model student, so as not to get entangled.
しないで 優雅 噛み付くほど欲しい
Please don't, gracefully, so much that I want to bite.
レディ レディ 甘えた方を見せてほしい
Lady, Lady, I want you to show me your spoiled side.
一緒に歌ってくれる？
Will you sing with me?
はみだしたい もっと 変われないの
I want to stand out more, can't I change?
自由型のアプローチは好き放題保存
Freestyle approach, as much as I like,
その塩梅 もっと
that balance, more...
戻れないの
Can't go back,
優しいフリしてただ焦らせる
pretending to be gentle, just teasing me.
二人とも、よくできました！
You two did a great job!
そっと効果をあげて 君を 魅せて君を
Softly increasing the effect, showing you off, showing you off.
そっと心をタップ 君を ああ君を
Softly tapping the heart, you, oh you.
知りたい ラストもお願い！
I want to know, one last time please!
はみだしたい もっと 変われないの
I want to stand out more, can't I change?
自由型のアプローチは好き放題
Freestyle approach, as much as I like,
その塩梅
that balance,
もう 戻れないの　優しい
I can't go back anymore,
優しいフリして ただ焦らせて もっと
pretending to be gentle, just teasing me more.
抜けないの
Can't escape it,
乱したウインク 戻したいけど
that messy wink, I want to undo it but...
そのポーカーもう 越えられないの
That poker face, I can't cross it anymore.
そもそもな話 まだ隠して
Essentially speaking, still hiding it,
見つめている
watching you.
はぁー、clumsy trickでしたー！
Phew, that was clumsy trick!
どうだったかな？
How was it?
最高！最高です！
Awesome! It was awesome!
ラプラスくんとあんなふうに一緒にパフォーマンスすることになるなんて…
To think I'd get to perform with Laplus-kun like that...
楽しかったな。
It was so much fun.
よかったら、こっちで一緒に話そうよ。
If you'd like, let's talk together over here.
ええっ！？行ってこいよ！
What?! / Go on!
いやいやいや、あの、ここが、ここがやっぱり落ち着くんですけど…
No, no, no, this is... this is really where I feel most comfortable, but...
さっきは一緒にステージにいてくれたのに？
Even though you were on stage with me just now?
行ってこいよ！望まれてるんだから！
Go on! You're the one being wanted!
え、今行きます！待っててください！
Ah, I'm coming now! Please wait for me!
がんばれー！
Good luck!
急に出てくるからびっくりしちゃったよ。
You came out so suddenly, you startled me!
申し訳ないです。なんか、もう我慢できなくて。
I'm so sorry. I just couldn't hold myself back anymore.
そんな破天荒なところが、ラプラスくんの魅力だよね。
That wild side of yours is your charm, Laplus-kun.
私も見習いたいよ。
I want to learn from you too.
いやもう、ひなみお姉さんはもうこのままで素敵です！
No, Hinami-oneesan, you are already wonderful just the way you are!
もうそのままでいてください！
Please stay just as you are!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
これからもお互いアイドルとしてがんばろうね。
Let's both keep doing our best as idols from now on.
あ、もう、恐れ多いです、ありがとうございます！
Oh, that's too much of an honor, thank you so much!
がんばります！
I will do my best!
またこうやって一緒に共演できたら嬉しいな。
I'd be so happy if we could perform together again like this.
あ、それももう、お、恐れ多…あ、ありがとうございます！
Ah, that's also too... too much of an... thank you so much!
今日はありがとう！
Thank you for today!
とっても素敵なミニライブでした！
It was a truly wonderful mini-live!
みんなも楽しんでくれたかな？
Did everyone enjoy it too?
それじゃあ、またね！
Well then, see you later!
ラプラスくんも！
You too, Laplus-kun!
え？ひなみお姉さん？
Huh? Hinami-oneesan?
あ、お姉さん…
Ah, Oneesan...
お姉さんっ！
Oneesan!